Bernard L. Fontana Papers 1832-2000 (bulk 1956-1985)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series I: Activity Files, 1859-2000
  - Subseries 1: Organizations
    - University of Arizona – Friends of the Library – Correspondence., undated; 1986 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - University of Arizona – Friends of the Library – Correspondence., 1987-1992 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - University of Arizona – Friends of the Library – Financial Records., 1983-1992 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - University of Arizona – Friends of the Library – Keepsake Publications., undated; 1984-1992 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - University of Arizona – Friends of the Library – Meeting Minutes., 1984-1992 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - University of Arizona – Friends of the Library – Membership Lists., 1983-1992 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - University of Arizona – Friends of the Library – Outings., 1985-1991 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - University of Arizona – Friends of the Library – Powell Endowment., 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - University of Arizona – Friends of the Library – Presented Talks., undated; 1984-1987 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - University of Arizona – Honors Convocations., undated; 1967-1977 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - University of Arizona – KUAT National Endowment for the Humanities., undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - University of Arizona – KUAT National Endowment for the Humanities., 1975-1978 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - University of Arizona – Library Borderlands Grant Application., 1992 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - University of Arizona – Library Collections Development Committee., undated; 1979-1984 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - University of Arizona – Library Collections Development Committee., 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - University of Arizona – Library Collections Development Committee., 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - University of Arizona – Library Collections Development Committee., 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - University of Arizona – Library Dedication Committee., 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - University of Arizona – Library History., 1991 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - University of Arizona – New Start., undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - University of Arizona – Program for New Faculty., 1976 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - University of Arizona – Special Collections., 1979-1985 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - University of Arizona – Special Collections Commission., undated; 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - University of Arizona – Town and Country Life Conference., 1978 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - University of Arizona Press – Book Promotions., 1974-1989 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - University of Arizona Press – Forewords, Correspondence, Reports., undated; 1970-1990 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - University of Arizona Press – Manuscript Evaluations (A – G)., 1971-1986 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - University of Arizona Press – Manuscript Evaluations (H - Z)., 1971-1987 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - University of Arizona Press – Of Earth and Little Rain Contract., 1989 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - University of New Mexico – Ronstadt Memoirs., 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Westerners International., 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Wheelwright Museum of the American Indian., 1989 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Writers of the Purple Sage – Bibliographies., 1983 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Writers of the Purple Sage – Down Mexico Way., 1983 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Writers of the Purple Sage – Faces of Pancho Villa., 1988 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Writers of the Purple Sage – Geronimo’s Surrender., 1985 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Writers of the Purple Sage – Golden West., undated; 1983-1984 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Writers of the Purple Sage – Grant Proposal., 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Writers of the Purple Sage – Indian Country – Inventing the Indian., 1985 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Writers of the Purple Sage – Indian Country – Meeting., 1985 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Old Southwest/New Southwest., 1985 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Writers of the Purple Sage – Organization Meeting., 1983 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Writers of the Purple Sage – Out West., undated; 1883-1984 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Writers of the Purple Sage – Radio Programs., 1984 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Writers of the Purple Sage – Resource Kits., 1983 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Writers of the Purple Sage – Tanque Verde Workshop., 1983 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Subseries 2: Projects and Research
    - Acoma and Laguna., 1955-1965 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Ak Chin Claims Case., undated; 1958-1968 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Alamo Hacienda – Beckford Kibbey Home., 1987 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Alamos – Rachael French., undated; 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - American Indian Periodicals., 1982-1984 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Apache Clippings., 1982-1984 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Arizona Academy Indians Clippings., 1971-1992 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Arizona and New Mexico Reservations., undated; 1969-1971 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Arizona History News., 1961-1970 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Arizona Indians., 1965-1973 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Arizona Indians – General Data., undated; 1954-1971 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Arizona Statehood., undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Arthur Schott Bibliography., undated; 1859-1959 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Bancroft Library – Sonora and Arizona Microfilm Project., 1985 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Bead Trade Natchitoches – C.H. Webb., undated; 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Brady’s Report., 1860 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Broken Arrow Center Proposal., 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Calabasas, Arizona., 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Camino del Diablo., 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Cartoons., undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Chaco Canyon., 1965 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Chiricahua Apache/U.S. Cessation of Hostilities., 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Cochiti Clippings., 1971 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Cocopa Indian Clippings., 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Colorado River Reservation., undated; 1940-1968 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Colorado River Reservation Clippings., 1967-1970 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Contemporary American Indian Life – Hipplerontemporary American Indian Life – Hippler., 1969 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Cordova, New Mexico., undated; 1979 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Corporation of Our Lady of Guadalupe., 1965 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Documentary Relations of the Southwest., undated; 1973-1975 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Documentary Relations of the Southwest., 1987 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Eye to the Past – Norman Barka TV Proposal., undated; 1976-1977 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - First Tucsonans – John Crouch Video Project., 1979 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Ft. Apache., undated; 1964-1968 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Ft. Apache Reservation., 1970-1972 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Ft. Bliss, Texas., undated (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Ft. McDowell and Salt River Reservations., undated; 1941-1965 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Ft. McDowell Clipping., 1973 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Ft. Yuma and Cocopa Reservation., undated; 1961-1991 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Gallup Area Office., undated; 1961-1965 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Garces Bicentennial., unidated; 1981 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - George Grant – Photographer., 1954-1984 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - George Kingsbury on Modoc Indian War., undated; 1961-1962 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Gila River and Ak Chin Reservations., undated; 1960-1970 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Gila River Reservation., 1970-1975 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Handbook of Latin American Art., 1981 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Handbook of Latin American Art - Joyce Bailey., undated; 1981-1985 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Handbook of North American Indians - Authors’ Instructions., undated; 1970-1980 (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Handbook of North American Indians - Biographical Articles., undated; 1972 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Handbook of North American Indians – Contemporary Indians., undated; 1970-1978 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Handbook of North American Indians – Indian and White Relations., 1971-1974 (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Handbook of North American Indians – Newsletters., undated; 1977-1983 (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Handbook of North American Indians – Technology and Visual Arts., undated; 1972-1976 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Havasupai Clippings., 1970-1975 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Havasupai Indian Reservation Addition., undated; 1974 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Hispanic Heritage – Jack Peterson TV Proposal., undated; 1983-1984 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Historical Archaeology – Iain Walker., 1965-1972 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - History of Indians of North America Lecture Notes., 1964 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Hopi., undated; 1962-1967 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Hopi and Navajo Clippings., 1970-1972 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Hopi Clippings., 1970-1972 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Huachuca Planning Visit., undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Hualapai and Havasupai Reservations., undated; 1939-1969 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Hualapai Clippings., 1970 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Hubbell Trading Post., 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Jack Kelly on Quechans., 1970 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Jemez, Zia, Santa Ana and El Rancho., 1954-1962 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Jicarilla – General., undated; 1963-1967 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Jicarilla Apache Clippings., 1970-1972 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - John P. Clum Letters., undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - John Russell Bartlett Illustrations., 1962-1983 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Kaibab-Paiute Economic Program., 1963-1967 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Kino’s Italy Tour., 1987 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Laird Guidebook to Arizona., 1985-1986 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Latin American Art., 1981 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Lead Crosses of Tucson., undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Linda Vista, Arizona., 1988 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Look to the Mountaintop Book., undated (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Maps., undated; 1944-1969 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Maricopa and Mayo Indian Pottery., undated; 1956-1968 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Mescalero Clipping., 1971 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Mescalero – General., undated; 1961-1964 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Mohave Clipping., 1971 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Mohave Indian Pottery., 1963 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Navajo Clippings., 1969-1973 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Navajo – Community Development., 1967-1972 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Eastern Navajo Agency., undated; 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Navajo – General Information., undated (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Navajo – General Information., 1953-1965 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Navajo – General Information., 1966-1972 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - New Mexico and Arizona Railroads., undated; 1959-1990 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - New Mexico Indians., undated; 1963-1973 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Newell Cantonement., undated; 1985 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Nuestra Señora de Valvanera I., undated; 1979-1984 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Nuestra Señora de Valvanera II., undated; 1980-1983 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Old Pueblo Cable Television Proposal., undated; 1981 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Overland Press – Hislop Letters., undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Overland Press – Hislop Letters., 1957-1966 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Paiute Indians Bridgeport, California., 1974 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - People, Places and Things Foreword., undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Phoenix Area Office – Bureau of Indian Affairs., 1965-1968 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Pima and Maricopa Clippings., 1878-1973 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Pima Bajo Indians – 1955 Trip. (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Pima Bajo Indians – 1966 Trip., undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Pima Battleground., undated; 1965-1986 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Pima Indian Claims Case., 1976 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Polish Theater., 1979 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Proto-Colonial Research Newsletters., 1987-1991 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Pueblo Clippings., 1973 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Quechan (Yuma) Clippings., 1970-1973 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Roberto Thompson Interview., 1963 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Ronald Ives., 1959-1960 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - San Antonio Curriculum Project., 1979-1981 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Sanctuary Movement., 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Saguaro National Monument – Buffer Zones., 1987-1988 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Saguaro National Monument – General Management Plan., 1986-1988 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Saguaro National Monument – Tucson Mountain Park., 1986-1989 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Salt River and Ft. McDowell Reserves., 1965 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - San Carlos Agency Workable Program., 1962-1973 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - San Carlos Apache Clippings., 1968-1973 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - San Carlos Apache – General., 1965-1967 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - San Ildefonso, Nambe, and Pojoaque., 1964-1965 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - San Juan, Santa Clara and Tesuque., 1964-1965 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - San Xavier and Papago Indians – Fiesta and Writings., undated; 1959-1973 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - San Xavier Booklet – Erni Cabat., 1984 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Sandia., 1954-1965 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Santa Cruz River Documentary., 1979 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Santa Fe – School and BIA Offices., undated; 1965-1967 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Santo Domingo, San Felipe and Cochiti., 1940-1965 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Seri Blue – A to Z., 1964-1965 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Seri Blue – Ed and Becky Moser., 1964-1965 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Seri Clippings., 1973 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Seri Indians – Turtle Bone Figurines., 1967 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Sonoran Heritage Program – Clothing (Envelope 1)., undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Sonoran Heritage Program – Clothing (Envelope 2)., undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Sonoran Heritage Program – Destiny., 1981 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Sonoran Heritage Program – Genius., 1980 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Sonoran Heritage Program – Information., 1978-1979 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Sonoran Heritage Program – Information., 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Sonoran Heritage Program – Making Connections., undated (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Sonoran Heritage Program – Play., undated (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Sonoran Heritage Program – Power., undated (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Sonoran Heritage Program – Work., undated (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Stewart Culin Papers., 1985 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Stewart Culin Papers., 1985 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Stewart Udall – Ten Year Planning Report., 1964-1971 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Taos and Picuris., 1963-1969 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Taos Clippings., 1965-1971 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Tonto Payson Apaches – Advocacy Team Concept., 1972 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Tonto Payson Apaches – Articles of Agreement., 1896 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Tonto Payson Apaches – The Camp by Nick Houser., 1971 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Tonto Payson Apaches – Clippings., 1970-1973 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Tonto Payson Apaches – General, undated (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Tonto Payson Apaches – General., 1970-1973 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Tonto Payson Apaches – Jackson Report., 1963-1972 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Tonto Payson Apaches – NCAI Resolution #6., 1970 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Tonto Payson Apaches – Position Paper (Sparks)., 1972 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Tucson 1912., undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Tucson Aqueduct., 1985 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Tucson at the Millenium., undated; 1999 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Twelve Travelers Sculptural Memorial., 1988-1990 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - United Pueblos Agency Materials., undated; 1954-1967 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - University of Arizona History., undated; 1982 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Ute Mountain Reservation., undated; 1952-1969 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Washington BIA materials., undated; 1963-1970 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - William Liesenbein – Ceramic Analysis., undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Yavapai – Camp Verde and Prescott., undated; 1966 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Yavapai Clippings., 1965-1971 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Yaqui Clippings., 1966-1978 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Yaqui – General., undated; 1966 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Zuni Clippings., 1970-1971 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Zuni – General., undated; 1962-1971 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Subseries 1: Organizations
    - Coronado., 1992 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Daughters of the Desert., 1986 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Gran Quivira Conference., undated; 1972-1979 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Gran Quivira Conference., 1980-1983 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Gran Quivira Conference XIII., 1984 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Gran Quivira Conference XIV., 1985 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Gran Quivira Conference XV., 1986 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Gran Quivira Conference XVI., 1987 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Gran Quivira Conference XVII., 1988 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Gran Quivira Conference XVIII., 1989 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Gran Quivira Conference XIX., 1990 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Gran Quivira Conference XX., 1991 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Gran Quivira Conference XXI., 1992 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Gran Quivira Conference XXIX., 2000 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Gran Quivira Conference - General., 1990-2000 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Health Education., 1966 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Historical Archaeology and the National Register., 1993 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - History and Identity: The Southwest in World Perspective., undated; 1979-1980 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Uto-Aztecan Ethnolinguistics., undated; 1981-1982 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Western History Conference., undated; 1961-1963 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Acadia, Amichel and Alava to Alaska., 1992 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - American Indian Ethnohistory., 1962 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Archaeology in the National Forests., 1975 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Arizona Indians: An Historic Overview., 1985 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Arizona-Sonora Desert Museum., 1979 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Before Humpty Dumpty., 1990 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Bones, Birds and Bugs., 1964 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - The Builders., 1997 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - The Burro: Adventures at Tar Flat., 1983 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Byrd Baylor., 1991 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Calabazas., 1975 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Charles F. Lummis Symposium., 1985 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Chickens to Phi Beta Kappa., 1996 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Coyotes Aren’t Tucson’s Only Howlers., 1991 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Daughters of the Desert: Women Anthropologists., 1986 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Drawing the Border., 1982-1983 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Excavating Ourselves., 1967 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Exodus., 1981 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Finding the Southwest., 1986-1987 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - The Fourth Age., 1984-1985 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Franciscans and Indian Missionary Work., 1961-1962 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - The Grand Canyon., 1990 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - A Half-Century of Greenfields., 1983 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - History is More or Less Bunk., 1988 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - History of the University of Arizona Library., 1985 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Indians and Missionaries in the Southwest., 1985-1986 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Introduction to the Southwest as a Region., 1985 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Inventing the Southwest., 1989 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Kino Three Centuries Later., 1987 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Library Tour., 1985 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Literati on the Line., 1982 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - Literature of Northwestern Mexico., 1990 (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - The Literature of Southeastern Arizona., 1992 (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - Man in the Desert., 1982 (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - Maynard Dixon: Arizona Artist., 1987 (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - Mesquite Wine., 1987 (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - Miscellaneous., undated; 1962-1984 (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - Miscellaneous - Ad Lib and from Slides., 1987-1990 (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - The Missions of Pimería Alta., 1961 (Box 16, Folder 45)
    - The Missions of Pimería Alta., 1962 (Box 16, Folder 46)
    - Myth and History., 1958 (Box 16, Folder 47)
    - New Perspectives., 1993 (Box 16, Folder 48)
    - Of Other Persuasion., 1979 (Box 16, Folder 49)
    - The Old Santa Cruz Trial., 1985 (Box 16, Folder 50)
    - One Hundred Years of Howard Why., 1958-1985 (Box 16, Folder 51)
    - Piman Indians of Green Valley., 1986 (Box 16, Folder 52)
    - The Piman Way and Christianity., 1987 (Box 16, Folder 53)
    - Presentation to Anthropology Class., 1966 (Box 16, Folder 54)
    - Preserving the Southwest., 1986 (Box 16, Folder 55)
    - Remarks on John P. Schaeffer., 1982 (Box 16, Folder 56)
    - San Xavier Mission., 1987 (Box 16, Folder 57)
    - San Xavier Mission Preservation., 1962 (Box 16, Folder 58)
    - San Xavier You’ve Never Known., 1961 (Box 16, Folder 59)
    - Saving San Xavier., 1990 (Box 16, Folder 60)
    - The Secret San Xavier., 1987 (Box 16, Folder 61)
    - The Secrets of San Xavier., 1986 (Box 16, Folder 62)
    - Sonora-California Trail., 1975 (Box 16, Folder 63)
    - Sonoran Peregrinations., 1979 (Box 16, Folder 64)
    - Spain’s Legacy in the United States., 1994 (Box 16, Folder 65)
    - Spanish in Arizona., 1979 (Box 16, Folder 66)
    - Stone to Stainless Steel., 1982 (Box 16, Folder 67)
    - Threads at St. Michael’s Mission., 1987 (Box 16, Folder 68)
    - To See the World., 1990-1991 (Box 16, Folder 69)
    - Tom Childs and Papago Indians., 1985 (Box 16, Folder 70)
    - Trailing the Santa Cruz., 1986-1990 (Box 16, Folder 71)
    - Trails to Tucson., 1989 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Tucson and Arizona: An Overview., 1991 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - University of Arizona., 1986 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - University of Arizona: Century One., 1985 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Untitled at Kitt Peak., 1984 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Untitled to Up with People., 1986 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - A View of the Holy Cross., 1997 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Wandering the Colorado Plateau., 1989 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Welcome to Tucson., 1985 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Welcome to University of Arizona., 1981 (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Series II: Writings
  Alphabetical. This series contains writings by Fontana and others. It is divided into three subseries.
  Subseries 1: Manuscripts: Contains manuscripts and related documents created by Fontana and others.
  Subseries 2: Book Reviews: Contains book reviews written by Fontana.
  Sunseries 3: Theses and Dissertations: Contains theses and dissertations written by students of Fontana.
  - Subseries 1: Manuscripts
    - After the War., undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Agent of God and King: Father Kino., 1987 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Alice Carpenter., 1986-1991 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - The American Way (1 of 2)., 1971 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - The American Way (2 of 2)., 1971 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - America’s Indian Landlords., 1959 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Antigua California., 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - An Arizona Classic., 1987 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Arizona and the West., 1981 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Battle on the Gila – Chronology., 1832-1940 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Battle on the Gila – Corrected Pages., 1986 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Battle on the Gila – Early Drafts (1 of 2)., undated (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Battle on the Gila – Early Drafts (2 of 2)., undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Battle on the Gila – Edited by Pat Shelton., undated (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Battle on the Gila – Final Draft 2., undated (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Battle on the Gila – Kroeber Correspondence., 1961-1987 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Battle on the Gila – Manuscript., undated (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Battle on the Gila – Notes and References., undated (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Battle on the Gila – Research., undated (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Battle on the Gila – Second Review., 1983-1986 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Battle on the Gila – Typed Index., 1986 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Battle on the Gila – Uncorrected Pages., undated (Box 18, Folder 2)